<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on Suriya&#39;s site</title>
    <link>https://suriya.cc/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on Suriya&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 22:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suriya.cc/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The future and The story</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/meta/the_future_and_the_story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/meta/the_future_and_the_story/</guid>
      <description>Companies are valued much higher when they are pursuing something super big, super into the future. eg, facebook =&amp;gt; meta, amazon =&amp;gt; cloud, etc
This is useful for companies to pump their valuation. see https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=30916357
this works because the future is unpredictable and un plannable. Which means that the only way we make sense of the future is through stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Morality</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/meta/on_morality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/meta/on_morality/</guid>
      <description>The whole world seems to be running on this flywheel of pump and dump schemes and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to matter as long the future is far enough.
Elon Musk The guy behind tesla, spaceX and other moonshot companies is an interesting study. For a sect of faithful followers he&amp;rsquo;s an engineer of unmatchable intelligence and insight into everything ranging from mars exploration to synthetic brain chips. Which&amp;hellip; To be honest, sounds a lot like a PT Barnum humbug, to say the least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surplus intellectual capacity</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/meta/surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/meta/surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>When I was around 13 or 14 I used to have this wild vision of the world, where everybody was optimising for the betterment of humanity and not &amp;ldquo;wasting&amp;rdquo; their brains on useless stuff like movie gossips and whatnots. My reasoning at the time was that, if only people around me wouldn&amp;rsquo;t bring in non-utilitarian information to me, I would be able to do &amp;ldquo;much&amp;rdquo; more. But in reality it was only my younger self, justifying being lazy and not actively doing stuff and just simply complaining everything around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Focus</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/meta/on_focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/meta/on_focus/</guid>
      <description>Experiment1 - Time based &amp;ldquo;focus&amp;rdquo; segments I generally don&amp;rsquo;t believe timing, focus is a bad way of doing it because. The belief is that, when you are in &amp;ldquo;focus&amp;rdquo;, you forget time and get all into it. But, this happens very rarely and hard to replicate.
At least in the short term, I strongly believe that I can gain a lot by segmenting my time.
Method Setup counter for a maximum of 2 hrs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing innovation</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/meta/missing_innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/meta/missing_innovation/</guid>
      <description>Historically, Most innovation has originated from developed nations and trickled down to developing ones, very much following the Trickle down efffect
And it makes sense. Creating new tech is costly and developing nations cannot afford such R&amp;amp;D costs. As the economy is cash strapped and there are many more mouths to feed. This asymmetry is why &amp;ldquo;developed nations&amp;rdquo; stay ahead of the curve while &amp;ldquo;developing ones&amp;rdquo; trod along. For example India created it&amp;rsquo;s first indigenous microprocessor as late as 2018 and India lags in tech among it&amp;rsquo;s asian counterparts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/meta/dead_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/meta/dead_projects/</guid>
      <description>layout: base type: page emoji: 🪦 title: Dead Projects description: Contemplating about the number of dead or half built projects. date: 2021-12-21 22:15:00
I have a lot of unfinished and dead projects. Sometimes, when I feel a little too good about myself. I like to scroll my github projects lists, just to get my eyes off the clouds and face reality :).
What is the point of all those repo&amp;rsquo;s if not as a reminder of bad coding and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/meta/scripty_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/meta/scripty_apps/</guid>
      <description>Some apps can be simple scripts accessible over the web running in a tiny tiny server. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
