<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacks on Suriya&#39;s site</title>
    <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacks on Suriya&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 22:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>superuser changes</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/superuser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/superuser/</guid>
      <description>When using aws a lot of times its annoying to type sudo for all commands. instead it is much simpler to just grant super user privileges to the ubuntu user only.
in the ubuntu shell do the following
sudo su - this should switch to a different type of shell. Now, you are in the root user shell.
from there, run
passwd ubuntu This should prompt you to set a new username password This is just icing on the cake for future use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>visualising Performance</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/profiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/profiler/</guid>
      <description>Interesting: Flame graphs don&amp;rsquo;t show sequentiality. They are not sorted based on time. They are sorted by alphabets. Which means in the flame graphs, if eg. here, the function h() was not run after b(). it&amp;rsquo;s after b() because it&amp;rsquo;s alphabetically after h()
the colours can either be random or provide another dimension (eg. sys calls in red)
Inlining code, makes it difficult to do debugging. JAVA has options to Inline code 9 levels deep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django issues and quick fixes</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/django/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/django/</guid>
      <description>CSRF token invalid __URL__ not in trusted origin
This happens because there is no CSRF_TRUSTED_ORIGINS in the settings file. Also make sure that the url does not have an end slash</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing jekyll for the first time and issues</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/ruby_v_xcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/ruby_v_xcode/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to install jekyll in my local machine and faced this error
/System/Library/Frameworks/Ruby.framework/Versions/2.6/usr/lib/ruby/2.6.0/mkmf.rb:467:in `try_do&amp;#39;: The compiler failed to generate an executable file. (RuntimeError) You have to install development tools first. this was fixed by running
sudo xcode-select -switch / I checked the manpages It seems like this changes the xcode scope to global. and makes available all the tools and env variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>local tunnels with cloudflare</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/local_tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/local_tunnels/</guid>
      <description>instantly being able to spin up a tunnel with https in my local machine is useful in a lot of cases
Resources https://developers.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-one/connections/connect-apps/install-and-setup/tunnel-guide/ There is a key.json file + config.yaml file. where all the routing details are stored.
these are located under ~/.cloudflare/
skip caching
go to page rules and add a page rule to cache level: Bypass https://community.cloudflare.com/t/unsolicited-utomatic-caching-via-argo-tunnels-at-cf-edge/308615
Downsides js is cached making it harder to do js development. (stale: 25Jul2022, use page rules) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ruby hack</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/ruby/</guid>
      <description>rvm is a tool to maintain a Ruby environment. rvm --default is a shortcut to set the default Ruby environment. rvm use is a shortcut to set the current Ruby environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for a self-hosted VPN</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/VPN/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/VPN/</guid>
      <description>Goals: Find a VPN solution that would be able to maintain an ACL. No licensing solutions OpenVPN - Not Truly self-hosted, in the sense that you will have to pay for the software in the range of $7 per user. Even if you self host it
Wireguard - only transmission security, no endpoint security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom user Agent for testing</title>
      <link>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/custom_ua/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suriya.cc/tech/hacks/custom_ua/</guid>
      <description>A user-agent is used to recognize the browser and the device the project, whatismybrowser.com have a database of user agents it&amp;rsquo;s just a string that says about your browser and device type that is sent as a cookie in every request. You can find your current user agent by googling &amp;ldquo;what is my user agent&amp;rdquo;
These are incredible in their own interesting way.
But, I was stuck with a problem of trying to simulate a device with user agent and inspect it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
